[{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"1. Nationalists in this country believe in a conspiracy that numbers representing the Basmala were code for a Muslim coup. Alleged members of Ata Ullah’s “Faith Movement” in this country were targeted during the Inn Din massacre. This country replaced citizenship for Arakanese people with a National Verification Card. Ashin Wirathu (“WEE-rah-thoo”) and other Buddhist monks in the 969 (“nine-six-nine”) Movement attempted to classify a minority in this country as Bengali as justification for a mass exodus from its Rakhine (“ruh-KYNE”) State to Bangladesh. For 10 points, name this country where the National League of Democracy under Aung San Suu Kyi (“owng SAN soo CHEE”) opposes the forced migration of the Rohingya (“ro-HIN-jah”) people. ","answer":"ANSWER: Myanmar [or Burma; or Republic of the Union of Myanmar] <CE/Geo/Other/Pop Culture> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"2. One method of analyzing this process involves finding the intersection of the Q line and two operating lines; that method is named for McCabe and Thiele (“TEEL-uh”). This process is equivalent to a series of flashes, and one can calculate an equivalent number of theoretical stages for this process using the Fenske equation. Some of the products of this process are returned to it in reflux. Vapor–liquid equilibrium is considered when designing apparatuses for this process, whose “fractional” form is used to refine petroleum. Solutions that cannot be separated by this process are called azeotropes. For 10 points, what process separates compounds by their boiling points? ","answer":"ANSWER: distillation [accept binary distillation or fractional distillation] <Chemistry> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"3. The protagonist of a story by this author sees stars “grouped in strange constellations” and hears “whispers in an unknown tongue” as he travels through a forest. In that story by this author, a disguised scout tricks a man by mentioning a “great quantity of driftwood.” This author calls a lawyer “one skilled in circumvention of the law” in a satirical collection that was first published as The Cynic’s Word Book. “A stunning blow” ends Peyton Farquhar’s (“FAR-quar’s”) vision of himself escaping his hanging by Union soldiers in a story by this author. For 10 points, name this author of The Devil’s Dictionary and “An Occurrence at Owl Creek Bridge.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Ambrose Bierce [or Ambrose Gwinnett Bierce] <American Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"4. During this conflict’s “August Round-Up,” the head of one political organization ordered the execution of a group of young women known as the “Thirteen Roses.” The “Twenty-Seven Points” served as the official ideology of one faction in this conflict, which later merged with the Traditionalist Communion. The paramilitary Blueshirts were largely responsible for executing the White Terror during this conflict. After the deaths of Emilio Mola and José Sanjurjo (“sahn-HOOR-ho”) in a pair of plane crashes, the eventual winner of this conflict was able to consolidate his position in the Falange party. For 10 points, name this conflict in which the Republicans were defeated by the Nationalist coalition led by Francisco Franco. ","answer":"ANSWER: Spanish Civil War [accept Guerra Civil Española] <European History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"5. In 2018, the MiniBooNE (“mini-boon”) experiment confirmed the earlier LSND observations that these particles can have changing quantum numbers. In 2018, one of these particles emitted by a blazar in Orion was detected by an Antarctic observatory. These are the only particles in the standard model that may be Majorana (“ma-yo-RA-na”) fermions. Fewer of these particles than expected were detected from the sun, a problem partially resolved by the Super-Kamiokande experiment, which provided evidence for their flavor oscillation. Along with a neutron and positron, one of these particles is emitted in beta-plus decay. For 10 points, name these neutral leptons with very little mass. ","answer":"ANSWER: neutrinos [accept electron neutrino, but do not accept or prompt on “electron”] <Physics> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"6. Upon death, the souls of these individuals were believed to join a pair of “indestructible” stars that circled the North Pole. The “Cannibal Hymn” describes a ritual in which these figures posthumously hunt and eat other gods to guarantee their eternal divinity. According to Jan Assmann (“yahn AHS-mahn”), these religious figures held the ultimate responsibility of dispelling chaos, or isfet (“ISS-fet”), and maintaining harmony, or ma’at. Early examples of these figures were interred in a necropolis at Abydos (“uh-BY-doss”), preceding a different locale of burial for these individuals, such as Khufu. For 10 points, name these religious and political leaders whose bodies were commonly stored in pyramids. ","answer":"ANSWER: pharaohs [prompt on ancient Egyptians; prompt on rulers of ancient Egypt or synonyms; prompt on Egyptian gods or Egyptian deities] <Religion> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"7. The fourth movement of a non-symphonic piece by this composer is often interrupted by quotations of “Da geh’ ich zu Maxim” (“dah GAY ish tsoo MOCK-sim”), a song from Franz Lehár’s (“LAY-harr’s”) operetta The Merry Widow. A side drum solo begins and ends the allegretto scherzando second movement of a piece by this composer whose introduction and third movement Elegia are in the “night music” idiom. In a piece by this composer that contains an “interrupted intermezzo,” two bassoons play a minor sixth apart to begin a “Game of Pairs”; that piece is named for featuring every instrument in the ensemble. For 10 points, name this composer who used elements of the folk music of his native Hungary in his Concerto for Orchestra. ","answer":"ANSWER: Béla Bartók [accept names in either order] <Classical Music> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"8. In a story [emphasize] titled for one of these animals, a “fifteen-minute nag” wins her races due to her “cavorting and straddling up” near the ends of the races. A character mocks his rival by interrupting him with the phrase “lost his bottle of oil” in a play titled for these animals. Quail shot is poured down one of these animals’ throats, which loses Jim Smiley a 40-dollar bet. Dionysus seeks to retrieve Euripides from the underworld as these animals repeat the refrain “Brekekekéx-koáx-koáx” in a play by Aristophanes. For 10 points, Calaveras County is the setting of a Mark Twain story about a “Celebrated Jumping” example of what amphibian? ","answer":"ANSWER: frogs [or batrachoi or ranae; accept The Frogs or “The Celebrated Jumping Frog of Calaveras County” or “Jim Smiley and His Jumping Frog” or “The Notorious Jumping Frog of Calaveras County”] <World/Other Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"9. This book contrasts the pluralism of Margaret Mead’s study of Papuan temperament with her narrow “feminine protest,” blaming the latter on a “freezing” adherence to strict functionalism. Other chapters in this book question the “Solipsism of Sigmund Freud” and “The Forfeited Self.” An interview series for Smith College grads prompted this book, whose first paragraph poses the “silent question, ‘Is this all?’” Later, this book laments Maslow’s prediction that the group in question will only reach self-actualization through other people and says that the title concept has buried millions of American women. For 10 points, name this 1963 book on “the problem with no name” by second-wave feminist Betty Friedan. ","answer":"ANSWER: The Feminine Mystique <Philosophy> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"0. In this colony, the Zappo Zap people allied with Europeans to crush the Kuba (“KOO-bah”) Kingdom and continue slave trading. Outcry over the summary execution of trader Charles Stokes in this colony helped motivate investigations of its affairs by E. D. Morel and Roger Casement. George Washington Williams coined the term “crimes against humanity” in an exposé denouncing abuses committed in this colony by groups like the Force Publique (“poo-BLEEK”), who enforced rubber quotas. At the Congress of Berlin, this colony was personally awarded to Leopold II of Belgium. For 10 points, name this central African colony that names a modern-day nation whose capital is Kinshasa. ","answer":"ANSWER: Congo Free State [or Belgian Congo; accept Democratic Republic of the Congo or DRC or Congo-Kinshasa; do not accept or prompt on “Republic of the Congo” or “Congo-Brazzaville”] <World History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"1. This word describes galaxies that are classified by the Fanaroff–Riley system based on their luminosity distribution and include Centaurus A and Cygnus A. Signals in this region of the electromagnetic spectrum are combined in a method developed by Martin Ryle called aperture synthesis. Astronomers use the “Very Large Array” to study this type of radiation. In 1932, Karl Jansky (“JAN-skee”) first detected emissions in this region of the electromagnetic spectrum from the Milky Way. Supermassive black holes surrounded by accretion disks are known as “quasi-stellar” sources of this radiation. For 10 points, name this form of electromagnetic radiation with the longest wavelength. ","answer":"ANSWER: radio waves [accept radio astronomy; accept radio emissions; accept radio galaxies] <Other Science> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"2. A church in this city has a tall, Roman-style temple façade overlapping a second, wider portico. The façade of another building in this city features patterns in pink marble above a two-story loggia (“LO-juh”) whose arches combine Gothic and Islamic influences. A church in this city is nicknamed the Church of Gold due to its ornate mosaics, which were likely originally created by Byzantine artisans. A palace in this city is linked to an adjacent prison by the Bridge of Sighs. This city is the site of Palladio’s San Giorgio Maggiore. For 10 points, name this city home to the Basilica San Marco and the Doge’s Palace, as well as many canals. ","answer":"ANSWER: Venice [or Venezia] <Other Arts> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"3. While passing through this state, the 6th Massachusetts suffered the first Union casualties of the Civil War while suppressing riots that began at its President Street Station. The Lincoln administration rejected a ruling by Roger Taney (“TAW-nee”) that a citizen of this state could not be held without habeas corpus in the case Ex Parte Merryman. After capturing a copy of Robert E. Lee’s Special Order 191, George McClellan fought a battle in this state that ended the first Confederate invasion of the North and led to the announcement of the Emancipation Proclamation. For 10 points, the Battle of Antietam was fought in what border state where federal troops blocked secessionist efforts in Baltimore? ","answer":"ANSWER: Maryland (The first line refers to the Pratt Street Riots.) <American History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"4. An editorial interlude from this novel describes the Farmer Lad murdering his replacement so that he cannot marry his employer. In this novel, characters play a game in which a woman hits them on the ear each time they make a mistake while counting. This novel shifts to third-person narration after its central character ends his correspondence with Wilhelm. After resigning as an ambassador’s assistant, a character in this novel returns to Walheim and passionately reads from his translation of Ossian (“OSH-in”). The title character of this novel borrows two pistols from Albert and kills himself after he fails to win the love of Lotte (“LAW-tuh”). For 10 points, name this epistolary novel by Goethe (“GUR-tuh”). ","answer":"ANSWER: The Sorrows of Young Werther [or Die Leiden des jungen Werthers] <European Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"2. This protein was first sequenced using FDNB by Frederick Sanger. GLUT4 (“gloot-four”) is regulated by this hormone, whose action is counteracted by glucagon. Beta cells in the islets of Langerhans secrete this hormone. For 10 points, what pancreatic hormone decreases blood glucose and is deficient in people with diabetes? ","answer":"ANSWER: insulin <Biology> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"6. An old woman mysteriously “bans” this character shortly before his death in a ballad preserved in the Percy folio. Two plays by Anthony Munday originated the legend that this character was the Earl of Huntingdon. In another legend, this character utters a quick prayer to the Virgin Mary before killing Guy of Gisbourne, mutilating his head, and presenting it to the Sheriff of Nottingham. This character roams Sherwood Forest alongside Friar Tuck, Little John, and the rest of his “Merry Men.” For 10 points, name this English folk hero who stole from the rich and gave to the poor. ","answer":"ANSWER: Robin Hood [or Robyn Hode; prompt on partial answer; accept Robin of Locksley] <Mythology> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"7. This thinker concluded that a society and the god that it worships are functionally equivalent after studying totemism among Australian Aboriginals. Ruth Benedict’s definition of culture as “personality writ large” riffs on this thinker’s definition of God as “society writ large.” This scholar proposed that religion was defined by creating a dichotomy of sacred and profane. This author of The Elementary Forms of the Religious Life instructed followers to “treat social facts as things.” Another of his studies contrasts the anomie (“ah-no-MEE”) of Protestant life with more communal Catholic societies, which have lower rates of self-slaughter. For 10 points, name this French sociologist who authored the monograph Suicide. ","answer":"ANSWER: Émile Durkheim <Social Science> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"8. A man breaks a rod over his knee on the right of this painter’s The Marriage of the Virgin, which features an octagonal shrine modeled after a similar one in the background of his teacher’s painting The Delivery of the Keys. In a painting by this artist, doctors of the church are identified by their names written in halos; that painting by this student of Perugino is part of a project that also includes his Parnassus and La Disputa. The Stanza della Segnatura houses a fresco by this artist that features elaborate arches and depicts Plato pointing upward at its center. For 10 points, name this Italian Renaissance painter of The School of Athens. ","answer":"ANSWER: Raphael [or Raphael Sanzio da Urbino] <Painting/Sculpture> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"9. When the narrator hears the name of this location, he remarks that it has “such magic power” that “the phantoms of those haunted late years began to take flight.” A man makes the sign of the cross on his deathbed after returning from Italy to die at this estate. A Christmas holiday spent at this estate is ruined by the presence of Mr. Samgrass, who was hired to control the drinking of a man who brought his teddy bear Aloysius to Oxford. After being invited by Lady Marchmain and her son, Sebastian Flyte, this estate is visited by the narrator, Charles Ryder. For 10 points, name this house that is “Revisited” in a novel by Evelyn Waugh (“EEV-lin WAH”). ","answer":"ANSWER: Brideshead [accept Brideshead Revisited] <British Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"0. Undisciplined troops under this ruler’s commander, Philibert of Châlon (“sha-LON”), murdered the captain Kaspar Röist as part of an event often cited as ending the Renaissance. After initially ridiculing one controversy as “an argument between monks,” this ruler presided over the opening of the Council of Trent. Long before his abdication to a monastery due to his gout, this ruler called Martin Luther to defend his views at the Diet of Worms (“vurms”). Victorious at Pavia, this first son of Joanna the Mad inherited the Netherlands, Austria, Aragon, and Castile into his domain. For 10 points, name this 16th-century Catholic monarch, the first Habsburg to rule over both the Holy Roman Empire and Spain. ","answer":"ANSWER: Charles V [or Charles I of Spain; accept Carlos I or Carlos V; prompt on Charles or Carlos] (The event in the first sentence is the 1527 Sack of Rome.) <European History> Bonuses "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Name this French composer and member of Les Six (“lay SEESE”) who wrote The Breasts of Tiresias. He only wrote operas late in his career, and his Dialogues of the Carmelites reflects his late religiosity and depression. ","answer":"ANSWER: Francis Poulenc (“frawn-SEESE poo-LANK”) "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] The Breasts of Tiresias was premiered at the Opéra-Comique, which has staged this Georges Bizet (“bee-ZAY”) opera over 2,500 times. Its numbers include a “Toreador Song” and a “Habanera.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Carmen "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] After singing her “Habanera,” Carmen throws a rose to this corporal. When she chooses the bullfighter Escamillo (“ess-ka-MEE-yo”) over him, this character murders her in a jealous rage. ","answer":"ANSWER: Don José (“zho-SAY”) <Other Arts> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Name this substance. The speaker sees a man “flound’ring like a man in fire or lime” after this substance foments an “ecstasy of fumbling” in the poem “Dulce et Decorum Est.” ","answer":"ANSWER: poison gas [accept phosgene gas or chlorine gas] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] This author described the “froth-corrupted lungs” of a man killed by poison gas in his poem “Dulce et Decorum Est,” which, like “Anthem for Doomed Youth,” is one of the many poems he wrote about World War I. ","answer":"ANSWER: Wilfred Owen "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] This poet wrote “After two thousand years of mass / We’ve got as far as poison-gas” in “Christmas, 1924.” This author described English military demonstrations just before World War I in his poem “Channel Firing.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Thomas Hardy <British Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Name this influential New York urban planner of the mid-20th century. He organized and planned projects like the Triborough (“TRY-bro”) and Verrazzano–Narrows bridges, Lincoln Center, and Shea (“shay”) Stadium. ","answer":"ANSWER: Robert Moses "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] One of Moses’s biggest achievements was bringing the headquarters of this intergovernmental organization to New York. This organization’s General Assembly and Security Council convene in a complex on the East River. ","answer":"ANSWER: United Nations [or UN] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Moses’s rise to power was aided by this governor of New York who was nicknamed the “Happy Warrior.” Anti-Catholic sentiment contributed to this man’s loss in the 1928 presidential election. ","answer":"ANSWER: Al Smith [or Alfred Emanuel Smith] <American History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Name this quantity that is equal to the standard deviation squared. ","answer":"ANSWER: variance [prompt on sigma squared; prompt on s squared] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] This other quantity measures the asymmetry of a probability distribution about the mean. It can be “negative” or “positive” depending on which side of the distribution has a longer tail. ","answer":"ANSWER: skewness [or word forms such as skewed or skewedness] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Variance and skewness are the “second” and “third” examples of these quantities, which quantify the shape of a distribution about its mean. ","answer":"ANSWER: moments [accept central moments or standardized moments] <Other Science> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Name this location. In a Gwendolyn Brooks poem, it is occupied by seven pool players who “sing sin” and “thin gin.” ","answer":"ANSWER: the Golden Shovel "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] A different Gwendolyn Brooks poem titled for one of these people ends, “I knew you, though faintly, and I loved, I loved you / All.” In another poem, one of these people says to another character, “Life for me ain’t been no crystal stair.” ","answer":"ANSWER: mothers (The poem is “Mother to Son” by Langston Hughes.) "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Brooks set her collection Annie Allen in this Midwestern city, which is called “Hog Butcher for the World” in a poem by Carl Sandburg. ","answer":"ANSWER: Chicago <American Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Give this statement, whose central sentiment was realized three years after its speaker’s death in 149 BC. This statement was appended to the end of each of its speaker’s speeches, even if they weren’t related. Either the original language phrase or an English translation is acceptable. ","answer":"ANSWER: “Furthermore, Carthage must be destroyed!” [or “Carthago delenda est”; accept “Ceterum autem censeo Carthaginem esse delendam”] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] One member of this specific familial branch would oppose Cato the Elder’s blustering by ending his own speeches with “Carthage must be saved.” A general from this family defeated Hannibal at the Battle of Zama. ","answer":"ANSWER: Scipio [accept Cornelii Scipiones; accept Scipio Africanus; accept Scipio Nasica Corculum; accept Publius Cornelius Scipio Africanus; accept Publius Cornelius Scipio Nasica Corculum] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] At Zama, Hannibal fought using the “war” variety of these huge land mammals, which were commonly captured on the Indian subcontinent in antiquity. ","answer":"ANSWER: war elephants <European History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Name these self-duplicating genetic elements, examples of which include LINEs, SINEs, and P elements. The Ac/Ds system is an example of these elements. ","answer":"ANSWER: transposons [or transposable elements or jumping genes; accept retrotransposons; prompt on TE] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Transposons and the Ac/Ds system were discovered in and make up roughly 85% of the genome of this crop. This descendant of teosinte (“tay-oh-SIN-tay”) was first domesticated roughly 10,000 years ago in Mesoamerica. ","answer":"ANSWER: maize [or corn; or Zea mays] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] The commonality of these transposons among primates make them useful for tracking human evolution. These transposons, the most common in the human genome, are derived from 7SL RNA. ","answer":"ANSWER: Alu (“AL-oo”) elements [or Alu sequences; or Alu repeats] <Biology> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Name this massive sculpture composed of 16 metal rhombuses stacked atop one another, which serves as a memorial for fallen soldiers. ","answer":"ANSWER: The Endless Column [or The Infinity Column; or Infinite Column] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Endless Column is part of a World War I memorial at Târgu Jiu, which also includes a sculpture titled for one of these objects of Silence, which is surrounded by hourglass-shaped seats. Judy Chicago’s The Dinner Party includes a large, triangular one of these things. ","answer":"ANSWER: tables [accept Table of Silence] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Endless Column and Table of Silence are by this Romanian sculptor, who created the Bird in Space series. ","answer":"ANSWER: Constantin Brâncuși (“brin-KOOSH”) <Painting/Sculpture> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Identify this branch of theology that includes Origen’s Contra Celsum. C. S. Lewis’s The Screwtape Letters falls under the purview of this field, which generally refers to all defenses of Christianity against its detractors. ","answer":"ANSWER: Christian apologetics [or apology or apologia; accept apologism; prompt on descriptive answers that indicate arguments for or in favor of Christianity] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] The Summa contra Gentiles is a well-known work of apologetics by this Doctor of the Church, who gave five possible arguments for the existence of God in his Summa Theologica. ","answer":"ANSWER: Saint Thomas Aquinas [accept Thomas of Aquino or Tommaso d’Aquino; prompt on Thomas; prompt on Doctor Angelicus; prompt on Doctor Communis] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] The subfield of moral apologetics, which emphasizes humans’ status as sinful creatures in need of redemption, is exemplified by this violent 1741 sermon given by Jonathan Edwards during the First Great Awakening. ","answer":"ANSWER: “Sinners in the Hands of an Angry God” <Religion> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Name this economic statement. Debate persists over the accuracy of the formulation of this statement by Keynes (“canes”) as “supply creates its own demand.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Say’s law "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Advocates of Say’s law are often followers of this economic philosophy with a two-word name. This philosophy asserts that the state should largely let the market be and minimize intervention. ","answer":"ANSWER: laissez-faire (“LESS-ay-FAIR”) "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Say’s law may imply that this thing is completely neutral. Its “narrow” definition only includes currency used as legal tender. ","answer":"ANSWER: money [accept M0, M1, or M2] <Social Science> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Name this Chinese explorer who led a fleet of massive treasure ships in voyages to Southeast Asia, India, and the Persian Gulf in the early 15th century. ","answer":"ANSWER: Zheng He (“jung huh”) [or Cheng Ho Ma He; or Ma Sangbao; prompt on He or Ho or Sangbao] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Zheng’s explorations occurred under this Chinese dynasty that ruled from 1368 until it was toppled by the Qing (“cheeng”). Zheng’s expeditions were briefly defunded amidst conflict by this dynasty against their predecessors, the Yuan (“yoo-EN”). ","answer":"ANSWER: Ming dynasty [or Empire of the Great Ming; or Ming Chao] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] This Ming emperor seized the throne with Zheng’s help and sponsored his voyages. This ruler moved China’s capital to Beijing and commissioned the Porcelain Tower and the Forbidden City. ","answer":"ANSWER: Yongle (“YUNG-luh”) emperor [or Zhu Di] <World History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Name this location that titles a series of novels about a lawyer’s encounters with the reincarnations of a friend identified by a pattern of three moles. ","answer":"ANSWER: sea [accept The Sailor Who Fell From Grace with the Sea or The Sea of Fertility; accept umi] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] The Sea of Fertility was written by this Japanese author of The Temple of the Golden Pavilion, who committed seppuku on television after a failed coup. ","answer":"ANSWER: Yukio Mishima [or Kimitake Hiraoka; accept names in either order] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Kochan tries to hide his homosexuality in a Mishima novel titled for the Confessions of one of these objects. These objects are sometimes tilted to change the amount of light cast upon them in Noh theater. ","answer":"ANSWER: masks [accept Confessions of a Mask] <World/Other Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Name these compounds that contain two alkoxy groups bonded to the same carbon. ","answer":"ANSWER: acetals (“ASS-uh-tals”) [or ketals; do not accept or prompt on “acetyls” – ask team to spell if necessary] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] In acetalization, water can be trapped using molecular sieves (“sivs”) that act as these materials. These materials, such as silica gel in packaged foods, absorb water to dry the surrounding area. ","answer":"ANSWER: desiccants [or desiccating agent] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] This element, which can be chelated (“KEE-lated”) by EDTA, forms sulfate and chloride compounds that are used as desiccants. This element is also found in fluorite and limestone. ","answer":"ANSWER: calcium [or Ca] <Chemistry> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Name this type of ensemble that plays Boccherini’s “Celebrated Minuet.” Variations of this string ensemble are named for whether they add an extra cello, viola, or a single guitar to a more popular ensemble. ","answer":"ANSWER: string quintet [accept viola quintet; accept cello quintet] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] For the last of his pieces for guitar quintet, Boccherini rearranged the Ritirata movement of a quintet evoking this city. Boccherini primarily worked in this city, whose nighttime street music inspired the aforementioned quintet. ","answer":"ANSWER: Madrid [accept Night Music of the Streets of Madrid or Musica notturna delle strade di Madrid] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Mozart wrote one G minor string quintet, but his better-known G minor pieces are “Great” and “Little” examples of this genre. Mozart’s forty-one pieces in this orchestral genre include “Jupiter.” ","answer":"ANSWER: symphony <Classical Music> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Name this pre-Socratic thinker credited with inventing the dialectic. One of his statements is translated as “everything flows and nothing abides,” reflecting his belief that “the only constant is change.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Heraclitus of Ephesus "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Hegel (“HAY-gull”) said that “there is no proposition of Heraclitus which I have not adopted” in the first lecture of a series on the philosophy of this concept. Hegel asserted that Africa did not have this concept because the world-spirit had not yet reached it. ","answer":"ANSWER: history [accept Lectures on the Philosophy of History] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] The first of the three laws of dialectic by this Young Hegelian (“huh-GAIL-ee-in”) borrows from Heraclitus’s thought on the “unity and conflict” of opposites. He worked with Karl Marx on The Communist Manifesto. ","answer":"ANSWER: Friedrich Engels <Philosophy> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Name this “Free City.” This “Queen” of a certain medieval organization was considered one of the “Five Glories” of the Holy Roman Empire, along with Florence, Rome, Pisa, and Venice. ","answer":"ANSWER: Lübeck [accept the Free City of Lübeck; accept the Adler von Lübeck or the Eagle of Lübeck] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Lübeck served as the leading city of this trade confederation that dominated Northern Europe during the Middle Ages. This organization constructed trading posts known as kontor from London to Novgorod. ","answer":"ANSWER: Hanseatic League [accept the Deutsche Hanse or the Hansa Teutonica; accept De Hanze] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Early Hanseatic voyages often had to deal with the Victual Brothers, a guild of individuals in this profession. Charles Johnson’s General History of these people mentions their common usage of the Jolly Roger flag design. ","answer":"ANSWER: pirates [accept A General History of the Pyrates; prompt on privateers] <European History> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Name this author of “The Viy” (“vee”). He described a man who believes he is the King of Spain in a story titled “Diary of a Madman.” ","answer":"ANSWER: Nikolai Gogol "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] After leaving his native Ukraine, Gogol moved to this former capital of Russia, where he set stories such as “Nevsky Prospect” and “The Overcoat.” ","answer":"ANSWER: St. Petersburg [or Sankt-Peterburg; accept Leningrad] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] After asking for help to recover his overcoat, Akaky Akakievich is rudely dismissed by a nameless character identified only by this adjective. Towards the story’s end, that character identified by this adjective has his overcoat stolen by Akaky’s ghost. ","answer":"ANSWER: prominent [accept rough synonyms such as important or significant; accept prominent personage; accept znachitel’ny or znachitel’noye litso] <European Literature> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Name these circuit components that store energy in a magnetic field. The namesake unit of these components is the henry. ","answer":"ANSWER: inductor [accept choke or reactor; prompt on coil] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Inductance manifests in two different ways. This form of inductance, in which two circuits are coupled by a magnetic field, is the basis for electrical transformers. ","answer":"ANSWER: mutual inductance [or mutual induction] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] This law of electromagnetism states that the current induced in a circuit due to a change in the magnetic field will oppose the change. It explains the minus sign on the voltage drop across an inductor. ","answer":"ANSWER: Lenz’s law <Physics> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"4. ","answer":"ANSWER: Georgia Tech [or Georgia Institute of Technology; prompt on GT or Tech] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Georgia Tech’s Cumberland win occurred under this coach. Baker Mayfield and Kyler Murrey are two recent winners of a trophy named for this man, which is given to the most outstanding college football player each year. ","answer":"ANSWER: John Heisman [accept Heisman Memorial Trophy] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"2. ","answer":"ANSWER: Herschel Walker <CE/Geo/Other/Pop Culture> "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Name this first of the five races of man in Greek mythology. They lived in an idyllic (“eye-DILL-ick”) age where no one worked and everyone was happy. ","answer":"ANSWER: Golden Race [or Race of Gold or chryseon genos; accept answers indicating a race that lived during the Golden Age] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] As Hesiod (“HEE-see-id”) recounted in his poem Works and Days, the Golden Race lived during the reign of this deity. In less peaceful stories, this king of the Titans castrated his father and swallowed his children. ","answer":"ANSWER: Kronos [or Cronus] "},{"tournament":"ACF Fall 2019","difficulty":"Difficulty: Easy College","round":"B","question":"[10] Although most mortals in Greek mythology are from the fourth race, the Race of Heroes, Apollonius of Rhodes wrote that this character was the last survivor of the Age of Bronze. This giant automaton guarded Crete until he was killed by Medea and the Argonauts. ","answer":"ANSWER: Talos <Mythology>"}]
